Chandra Sekhar Bandi

cs.bandi@gmail.com +91-9880021437

Summary

Software Test Lead with 10.5 years of experience in manual and automated testing. Involved in Test management and execution in agile and traditional development models. Designed test automation frame works and developed automated tests with expertise in using HP suite of Products for test management and automation activities.

Professional Experience

| April, 2005 – April 2014 | Systems/Software Engineer (Expert level) at PPS R&D Hub of Hewlett Packard India Software Operations, Bangalore |
|-----------------------------|---|
| December, 2003 – April,2005 | Software Engineer at Ampersand Software Applications Limited (renamed PK4 solutions), Bangalore |

Qualification

Bachelors of Technology in *Computer Science and Engineering* from Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University, Hyderabad in 2002

Skill set

| Test Management | HP Quality Center (ALM), Bugzilla, Rally (Agile) |
|-----------------|---|
| Test Automation | HP Unified Functional Testing (QTP), Selenium, HP Loadrunner, SoapUI, and OpenSTA |
| Scripting | Vbscript, Perl |
| Database | MS SQL Server, MySQL, SQLite |
| Source Control | Subversion |

Detailed Skill Summary

HP Quality Center (ALM):

- Created and managed tests, requirements, linking and tracking defects
- Generated, managed and ran automated scripts of types QTP, VAPI-XP, PERL in QC.
- Used QC's Open test architecture APIs to develop scripts to remotely access data, run tests and update information to the server
- Experience in creating automated tests, tracking and report generation
- Created scripts to migrate data between different projects & versions of Quality Center

HP Quick Test Professional

- Created hybrid frameworks to overcome limitations of QC & QTP in a distributed test environment.
- Estimated, planned and developed scripts using advanced scripting techniques. Automated test suites, debugged script issues, maintained automated tests and tracked test runs & failures
- Experience in automating stand-alone GUI driven applications.
- Automated localization test suites for supporting product in 10 languages leveraging a generic framework
- Provided multiple trainings on QTP to wider audience across the organization
- Advocated, mentored and supported teams on automation using QTP
- Received appreciation from Product architects (of HP QTP) for the framework developed to address distributed testing

Manual Testing:

- Experience in writing Test Plans, Review of test artefacts, Test Planning and Management
- Designing Test cases based on Requirements/Design documents
- Experience of working in Agile development environment besides traditional development models
- Experience in various Testing methodologies viz. Functional, Regression, Localization, Exploratory
- Contributed to Lean Six sigma projects

Automation and Others:

- Experience in developing automated scripts using PERL and vbscript
- Basic programming knowledge using Java and C#
- Exposure to API testing in web applications using SOAPUI
- Exposure to Selenium, IBM Rational Functional Tester, Eggplant (Macintosh)
- Exposure to Performance test tools –HP Loadrunner, Jmeter and OpenSTA
- Exposure to Jenkins and CruiseControl for Continuous Integration
- Contributed to Organization level initiatives of exploring new market avenues by being part of chosen group of professionals.
- Part of customer interaction initiatives of organisation
- Worked on Windows, Linux, Macintosh platforms to setup and test
- Well versed with setting up servers, configuring (RAID, hardware) & troubleshooting of systems/network issues
- Knowledge of printing standards (JDF, PPML) and technologies
- Completed a certificate course in "Software Quality Assurance & Management" from Indian Institute of Science, Bangalore. (Duration: 6 months)
- Successfully completed a Basic course (Level-1) in FRENCH from Alliance Française, Bangalore. (Duration: 6 months)

Projects Information

| Product | HP Smartstream Production Pro Print Server | |
|-----------------|--|--|
| Duration | April 2005 – April 2014 | |
| Version | 2.0 to 5.0 (Multiple versions of the product over 9 years) | |
| Environment | J2EE, Windows 2008 server R2, My SQL, Orblite, C# .Net, MS SQL Server, RESTful web server(tomcat) | |
| Manual Testing | Designed Test plans, test cases and executed Functionality, System, Usability Regression and Performance tests Coordinated with development team to plan testing- reproducing, tracking of defects and managing requirement changes Efficiently managed a 4 member test team to drive QA efforts from India Represented QA team in Scrum meetings for coordination and planning Supported field staff with hotfixes validation, customer defect reproduction Supported automation team with utilities for installation, integration of builds Designed performance tests & jobs for product by capturing benchmarked data Played a key role in the team by providing product technical and test expertise to ensure good quality Provided timely metrics to management | |
| Automation | Designed automation framework and maintained scripts for distributed test environment using PERL, QC, QTP covering Sanity and Basic Functionality test suites of the product bringing in savings of 7 Engineer-Days days per build. Used descriptive programming approach of QTP to develop scripts to capture Localization screens for ten languages for Field support/User manual resulting in savings of 27 Engineer-Days per iteration resulting in savings to organisation Debugging and maintaining of automated scripts across multiple version of product with integrated reporting in QC Automated test runs, analysis debugging and maintenance Validated automation tools for analysis(Selenium, Test) | |
| Product Details | HP Indigo digital presses transformed the commercial and industrial printing industry with patented liquid electro photography technique. These high speed devices are driven by a versatile, digital front-end (Print server) that aids in print job submission, tracking, and custom workflow management. The Pro print server processes variety of file types routing them to various presses at a high speed. HP keeps enhancing the software for HP Indigo press with Hot fixes and upgrades whilst providing new features and customer requested features. The latest version of product brings in new architecture migrating legacy code from C++ to C#.Net and replacing the Java based SWT UI with a web based UI served by a RESTful web server. | |

| Project | Parts Online -Black & Decker Hardware & Home Improvement | |
|-----------------|---|--|
| Duration | August 2004 – March 2005 | |
| Environment | ASP.NET, VB.NET, MS Commerce Server 2002, MS SQL Server | |
| Scope of work | Manual Testing of the functionality, pricing and e-commerce features, Review of requirement and preparing Test cases Testing credit card validation, defect tracking and management | |
| Project Details | The purpose of the Parts Online project is to deploy a web application that facilitates BDHHI's customers to place and track their orders online and to provide wizard interfaces for their product brands. It's a typical e-commerce application involving a purchasing to fulfilment of orders with credit card validation. | |
| Project | Sakata B&P Websites | |
| Duration | August 2004 – March 2005 | |
| Environment | ASP.NET, VB.NET, MS SQL Server | |
| Scope of work | Manual Testing of the portal, review of requirement, preparing Test cases Defect tracking and management | |
| Project Details | Sakata Seed America, Inc (SAI) is a leading seed company in North America wishes to deploy a generic template based portal that will allow SAI employees to publish new websites with minimal effort and update the content of the newly created brand websites. This will allow the non-programmers to create a new websites or update the content for the existing sites in a short time at a fraction of the cost. | |
| Product | Impel (Sales and CRM product) | |
| Duration | April 2004 – March 2005 | |
| Environment | Zerocode(proprietary tool), MS SQL Server | |
| Scope of work | Manual Testing of the portal, pricing and e-commerce features Understand new requirements (enhancements) and prepare Test cases Regression and Functional testing of the product | |
| Product Details | Impel is one of the prestigious products of Ampersand. It's a CRM product targeting small and medium enterprises. It's equipped with a variety of features and great user-friendly environment. With integrated sales, marketing & customer support modules, it ensures a 360-degree view of customer interactions | |

Personal Details:

| Passport | Available with a valid US - B1 Visa |
|---------------|-------------------------------------|
| Date of Birth | 28-09-1980 |

~~~~